{
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Which of the following tag is used to mark a begining of paragraph?",
      "a": "<td>",
      "b": "<te>",
      "c": "<p>",
      "d": "<dir>",
      "correct_answer": "<p>",
      "genre": "HTML"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following features of UNIX may be used for inter process communication?",
      "a": "Signals",
      "b": "Pipes",
      "c": "Semaphore",
      "d": "All of these",
      "correct_answer": "All of these",
      "genre": "Unix"
    },
    {
      "question": "Correct HTML tag for the largest heading is ......",
      "a": "<heading>",
      "b": "<h6>",
      "c": "<h1>",
      "d": "<head>",
      "correct_answer": "<h1>",
      "genre": "HTML"
    },
    {
      "question": "In Descendant Selector , style is applied to element based on ......",
      "a": "whether element have sub element or not",
      "b": "whether element have only 2 sub elements or not",
      "c": "whether element is of particular type or not",
      "d": "None of These",
      "correct_answer": "whether element have sub element or not",
      "genre": "CSS"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which property is used to specify typefaces?",
      "a": "font-family",
      "b": "font-name",
      "c": "font-face",
      "d": "font-type",
      "correct_answer": "font-family",
      "genre": "CSS"
    },
    {
      "question": "HTML stands for?",
      "a": "Hyper Text Markup Language",
      "b": "High Text Markup Language",
      "c": "Hyper Tabular Markup Language",
      "d": "None of these",
      "correct_answer": "Hyper Text Markup Language",
      "genre": "HTML"
    },
    {
      "question": "From which tag descriptive list starts ?",
      "a": "<LL>",
      "b": "<DD>",
      "c": "<DL>",
      "d": "<DS>",
      "correct_answer": "<DL>",
      "genre": "HTML"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following abstract data types can be used to represent a many to many relation?",
      "a": "Tree",
      "b": "Plex",
      "c": "Graph",
      "d": "Both (b) and (c)",
      "correct_answer": "Both (b) and (c)",
      "genre": "Data Structures"
    },
    {
      "question": "A mathematical-model with a collection of operations defined on that model is called .....",
      "a": "Data Structure",
      "b": "Abstract Data Type",
      "c": "Primitive Data Type",
      "d": "Algorithm",
      "correct_answer": "Abstract Data Type",
      "genre": "Data Structures"
    },
    {
      "question": "The minimum number of comparisons required to determine if an integer appears more than n/2 times in a sorted array of n integers is ......",
      "a": "O(n)",
      "b": "O(log n)",
      "c": "O(log n * n)",
      "d": "O(1)",
      "correct_answer": "O(log n)",
      "genre": "Data Structures"
    },
    {
      "question": "The information about an array that is used in a program will be stored in ......",
      "a": "Symbol Table",
      "b": "Activation Record",
      "c": "System Table",
      "d": "Dope Vector",
      "correct_answer": "Dope Vector",
      "genre": "Data Structures"
    },
    {
      "question": "The data structure required to evaluate a postfix expression is .....",
      "a": "Queue",
      "b": "Stack",
      "c": "Array",
      "d": "Linked List",
      "correct_answer": "Stack",
      "genre": "Data Structures"
    },
    {
      "question": "The data structure required to check whether an expression contains balanced parenthesis is .....",
      "a": "Queue",
      "b": "Stack",
      "c": "Array",
      "d": "Tree",
      "correct_answer": "Stack",
      "genre": "Data Structures"
    },
    {
      "question": "The postfix form of A*B+C/D is ......",
      "a": "*AB/CD+",
      "b": "AB*CD/+",
      "c": "A*BC+/D",
      "d": "ABCD+/ *",
      "correct_answer": "AB*CD/+",
      "genre": "Data Structures"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following data structure may give overflow error,even though the current number of element in it is less than its size?",
      "a": "Simple queue",
      "b": "Circular queue",
      "c": "Priority Queues",
      "d": "None of these",
      "correct_answer": "Circular queue",
      "genre": "Data Structures"
    },
    {
      "question": "The initial configuration of a queue is a, b, c, d, ('a' is in the front end). To get the configuration d, c, b, a, one needs a minimum of .......",
      "a": "2 deletions and 3 additions",
      "b": "3 deletion and 2 additions",
      "c": "3 deletions and 3 additions",
      "d": "3 deletions and 4 additions",
      "correct_answer": "3 deletions and 3 additions",
      "genre": "Data Structures"
    },
    {
      "question": "A complete binary tree with the property that the value at each node is at least as large as the values at its children is called .....",
      "a": "Binary search tree",
      "b": "Binary tree",
      "c": "Completely balanced tree",
      "d": "Heap",
      "correct_answer": "Heap",
      "genre": "Data Structures"
    },
    {
      "question": "Traversing a binary tree first root and then left and right subtrees called ........ traversal",
      "a": "postorder",
      "b": "preorder",
      "c": "inorder",
      "d": "none of these",
      "correct_answer": "preorder",
      "genre": "Data Structures"
    },
    {
      "question": "In tuple relational calculus P1 â†’ P2 is equivalent to ......",
      "a": "(not) P1 OR P2",
      "b": "P1 OR P2",
      "c": "P1 AND P2",
      "d": "P1 AND (not) P2",
      "correct_answer": "(not) P1 OR P2",
      "genre": "Database"
    },
    {
      "question": "The natural join is equal to .....",
      "a": "Cartesian product",
      "b": "Combination of Union and Cartesian product",
      "c": "Combination of selection and Cartesian product",
      "d": "Combination of projection and Cartesian product",
      "correct_answer": "Combination of selection and Cartesian product",
      "genre": "Database"
    },
    {
      "question": " In networking terminology UTP means ......",
      "a": "Unshielded Twisted Pair",
      "b": "Ubiquitious Teflon Port",
      "c": "Uniformly Terminating Port",
      "d": "Unshielded T-connector Port",
      "correct_answer": "Unshielded Twisted Pair",
      "genre": "Networks"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following cannot be declared static?",
      "a": "Class",
      "b": "Object",
      "c": "Functions",
      "d": "Both (a) & (b)",
      "correct_answer": "Both (a) & (b)",
      "genre": "OOP"
    },
    {
      "question": "With a single resource, deadlock occurs .....",
      "a": "if there are more than two processes competing for that resource",
      "b": "if there are only two processes competing for that resource",
      "c": "if there is a single process competing for that resource",
      "d": "none of these",
      "correct_answer": "none of these",
      "genre": "OS"
    },
    {
      "question": "Artificial neural network used for .....",
      "a": "Pattern Recognition",
      "b": "Classification",
      "c": "Clustering",
      "d": "All of these",
      "correct_answer": "All of these",
      "genre": "Soft Computing"
    },
    {
      "question": "In which of the following gates, the output is 1, if and only if at least one input is 1?",
      "a": "NOR",
      "b": "AND",
      "c": "OR",
      "d": "NAND",
      "correct_answer": "OR",
      "genre": "Digital Logic"
    },
    {
      "question": "In artificial Neural Network interconnected processing elements are called .....",
      "a": "nodes or neurons",
      "b": "weights",
      "c": "axons",
      "d": "Soma",
      "correct_answer": "nodes or neurons",
      "genre": "Soft Computing"
    },
    {
      "question": "The graph that shows basic blocks and their successor relationship is called ......",
      "a": "DAG",
      "b": "Flow graph",
      "c": "Control graph",
      "d": "Hamiltonion graph",
      "correct_answer": "Flow graph",
      "genre": "Compilers"
    },
    {
      "question": "Relocation bits used by relocating loader are specified by .....",
      "a": "relocating loader itself",
      "b": "linker",
      "c": "assembler",
      "d": "macro processor",
      "correct_answer": "linker",
      "genre": "Compilers"
    },
    {
      "question": "The subcategories of orthographic projection are .....",
      "a": "cavalier, cabinet, isometric",
      "b": "cavalier, cabinet",
      "c": "isometric, dimetric, trimetric",
      "d": "isometric, cavalier, trimetric",
      "correct_answer": "isometric, dimetric, trimetric",
      "genre": "Computer Graphics"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the maximun number of dimensions an array in C may have?",
      "a": "2",
      "b": "8",
      "c": "20",
      "d": "No limit. Depends on memory size.",
      "correct_answer": "No limit. Depends on memory size.",
      "genre": "C"
    },
    {
      "question": "The main reasons for the success of pipes are ....",
      "a": "The availability of many filter programs",
      "b": "UNIX treats devices as files",
      "c": "It provides a 2-way communication channel",
      "d": "Both (a) and (b)",
      "correct_answer": "Both (a) and (b)",
      "genre": "Unix"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following are not filter programs?",
      "a": "date",
      "b": "sort",
      "c": "cat",
      "d": "grep",
      "correct_answer": "date",
      "genre": "Unix"
    },
    {
      "question": "The order in which operands are evaluated in an expression is predictable if the operator is .....",
      "a": "*",
      "b": "+",
      "c": "%",
      "d": "&&",
      "correct_answer": "&&",
      "genre": "OOP"
    },
    {
      "question": "Main container for <TR>, <TD> and <TH> is ......",
      "a": "<TABLE>",
      "b": "<GROUP>",
      "c": "<DATA>",
      "d": "All of these",
      "correct_answer": "<TABLE>",
      "genre": "HTML"
    },
    {
      "question": "XPATH used to .....",
      "a": "Address your documents by specifying a location path",
      "b": "Address the server",
      "c": "Store the IP address of the server",
      "d": "None of these",
      "correct_answer": "Address your documents by specifying a location path",
      "genre": "XML"
    },
    {
      "question": "Well formed XML ....",
      "a": "meets certain grammatical rules outlined in the XML 1.0 specification",
      "b": "doesn't contain DTD's",
      "c": "is full of formula's",
      "d": "none of these",
      "correct_answer": "meets certain grammatical rules outlined in the XML 1.0 specification",
      "genre": "XML"
    },
    {
      "question": "<Base> tag is designed to appear only between ....",
      "a": "<HEAD>",
      "b": "<TITLE>",
      "c": "<BODY>",
      "d": "<FORM>",
      "correct_answer": "<HEAD>",
      "genre": "HTML"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which tag creates a number/order list?",
      "a": "<UL>",
      "b": "<OL>",
      "c": "<OT>",
      "d": "None of these",
      "correct_answer": "<OL>",
      "genre": "Unix"
    },
    {
      "question": "A high speed communication equipment typically would not be needed for ....",
      "a": "E-mail",
      "b": "transferring large volume of data",
      "c": "supporting communication between nodes in a LAN",
      "d": "all of these",
      "correct_answer": "E-mail",
      "genre": "Networks"
    },
    {
      "question": "The parameter passing mechanism for an array is .....",
      "a": "call by value",
      "b": "call by value-result",
      "c": "call by reference",
      "d": "none of these",
      "correct_answer": "call by reference",
      "genre": "C"
    }
  ]
}
